Every story has a beginning.
每个故事都有一个开始
Before the gates of Troy.
特洛伊木马战之前
In a certain house at Ithaca.
伊萨卡岛上的一座房子里
Upon the road to Thebes.
通往底比斯城的路上
但是无论始于何方
But no matter where it starts,
every story has its hero.
每个故事都有自己的英雄
As often as not,
有的时候
a young man on a journey
from innocence to experience.
是一个年轻人从纯真走向成熟
Morse
Morse.
Alistair 能谈谈吗?
Ah, Alistair! Might I have a moment?
如果是有关今晚的事的话
我已经说得很清楚了 院长
If it's about this evening, Master,
I've made my views clear.
Alistair, I do understand
how upsetting all this must be...
Alistair 我知道这一切肯定很让人难过...
# I know you're angry, baby
# But I'm gonna make it up to you
# Gonna make it up to you soon
# I know you're angry, baby
# But I'm gonna make it up to you
Hey!
# I'm gonna make it up to you... soon
# Oh, yes
# I won't dance for anyone
# But I will dance for you
# I wouldn't sing for anything
# But I could sing for you
# And I...
# I won't kill for anyone
# But I would kill for you
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
# Tell me where to lie
# Tell me what to say
# Tell me what to do
# It is all for you
# You can break my bones
# You're the song I sing
# Between clenched teeth, cos...
# I wouldn't dance for anyone
# But I'd dance for you...
Good evening, gentlemen.
好了
Right...
Booth Hill
Booth Hill.
# ..I would sing for you
# And... I wouldn't die for anyone
# But I would die for you
# I'd die...
# I would die for you...
Aargh.
# Cos... I wouldn't die for anyone
# But I would die, yeah
# I would die
# For...
# You... #
Morse
Morse.
Witnesses?
目击者?
那边那个女人听到了刹车声
Woman over the way heard a squeal of
brakes.
等她到窗口的时候 车已经开走了
By the time she got to the window,
the car was gone.
- 这是什么时候的事情?
- 半小时前
When was this?
About half an hour since.
Before eight. Nothing they could do.
He was already gone by the time they
got here.
八点前 救护人员做不了什么
他们到的时候他已经死了
No identification. We have to wait
on next of kin coming forward.
没有证件 我们只能等亲属前来认人了
How was he found?
Eh?
- 他是怎么被发现的?
- 啊?
The body. Where was it?
尸体 原本在哪?
就在那边的马路上
Oh, up against the kerb there.
That's what's done for him,
according to the ambulance boys.
据救护人员说 那要了他的命
头上撞得一塌糊涂
Head's a terrible mess.
那残留物呢?
What about debris?
这样的车祸 肯定会有玻璃
Something like this, you'd expect
there to be glass from...
the windscreen or headlamps.
比如挡风玻璃或者车前灯
Not always. Depends where it's
caught him.
不一定 要看他撞到了哪里
And how fast they were going.
还有开车速度
When it comes to traffic accidents,
rhyme and reason are out the window,
matey.
这种交通事故是没办法解释的 伙计
All aboard!
请大家上车
- Morse
- 早上好 长官
Morse.
Morning, sir.
公车罢工了 我答应送她去银行
Buses have called a strike.
I said we'd drop her at the bank.
Come on, Joan. Don't dawdle.
快点 Joan 别磨蹭了
- 早上好
Morning.
Haven't seen you about for a while.
有阵子没见到你了啊
Uh... no. No, I've been on
general duties.
呃 是啊 我现在负责值班
Where's Peter, then, this morning?
那Peter今天早上在哪?
Jakes警长? 他要出庭
Sergeant Jakes? He's got court.
你嘴巴可真严啊?
Don't give much away, do you?
我觉得我应该少说点 不是吗
I...don't think I'm meant to, am I?
Work, you know?
工作性质 你懂的
嗯 我懂
Oh, I know.
Is he still with that Sandra?
他还和那个Sandra在一起吗?
- 谁? Jakes?
- 没事了
Who? Jakes?
Never mind.
All out of Navy Cut.
I had to make do with Ribbon.
水手型烟丝卖完了 我只好买了缎带型的了
(不同的切丝方法)
没啥事?
Never mind what?
Work. If you must know.
I was asking about work.
工作 如果你非要知道 我在问他工作
可是他跟你一样 一句话也问不出来
Only, he's like you. It's like
trying to get blood out of a stone.
Quite right. You don't have time to
sit gassing. You can walk from here,
can't you?
应该的 说起来你可没时间坐着唠叨了
你从这自己走过去吧?
Save us going round the one-way.
省得我们还得饶单行道
All right. Well, thanks for
half a lift.
好吧好吧 多谢你送了我半程
Uh-uh. Nicely, please.
You want picking up.
诶诶 态度好点 下班你还要人来接呢
回见 Morse
Morse.
昨晚有什么情况吗?
Anything in last night?
was stolen from outside a transport
stop on the Botley Road last night.
一辆装满价值1万镑香烟的卡车 昨晚在Botley路旁的一个休息站外被偷了
We've been asked to be on
the lookout.
上面要我们调查这件事
Right, sir. Anything else?
好的 长官 还有别的事情吗?
Oh, actually, there was one other
thing.
噢 确实 确实还有件事
Morse's results came back from
the range.
Morse的射击考试结果出来了
Sergeant's exam is coming up,
isn't it?
接下来是警长考试是吧?
Yes, sir. Next week.
是的 下周
Won't count towards his mark,
of course,
这不会算在他成绩里
但是总督察对能达到这样成绩的人总是很看重
but the Chief Constable sets
great store by such things.
No-one come forward to claim him?
还没人来认领吗?
Not yet.
I've bagged his personal effects.
- 还没
- 我已经把他的个人物品装起来了
但别抱太大希望
But I wouldn't get your hopes up.
Just the usual. Specs.
都是些常见的 眼镜
抽烟的家伙 钥匙 钱包
Smoker's bits and bobs.
Keys. Wallet.
Somebody saw the accident, did they?
有人看到事故发生是吗?
No. Why?
没有 怎么了?
像这种案子 我通常会在小腿上发现撞伤
A case like this, I'd normally
expect to find some injury
to the lower limbs.
身体和汽车相撞的撞击点
Point of impact. Where the body's
come into contact with the vehicle.
Outside of the head injury,
there's not a mark on him.
但是除了头上的伤口 他身上没有其他伤痕
Could have been a glancing blow,
I suppose,
我估计可能撞得不是很重
tossed him into the air...
and the kerb's done the rest.
只是撞飞了 然后撞到了马路牙子
Uniform brought it in about an hour
ago. In the next street to that hit
and run. Opened.
制服警一小时前拿来的
就在肇事逃逸隔壁那条街 箱子开着
Anything to say it's the victim's?
Just essays, unmarked,
on The Trachiniae.
- 可以证明是死者的东西吗?
- 只有些没打分论文 有关特拉基斯少女的
Sophocles(古希腊悲剧诗人)的悲剧
It's a tragedy by Sophocles.
I took it the owner of the case
must be a Greats don,
我觉得箱子的主人是教古典文学的老师
所以我给各学院打了电话
so I rang around the colleges.
论文上的名字查到是Baidley学院的本科生
Names on the essays match undergrads
at a Baidley College
- 任课老师是Coke Norris教授
being tutored by a Professor Coke
Norris.
Doesn't mean to say he's the victim.
- 但那不代表他就是死者
There's no answer on his home number
and he hasn't turned in for work this
morning.
他家电话没人接 而且据门卫所说
他今天早上没有去上课
What about the driver? The car that
hit him must have been damaged.
那司机呢? 撞他的那部车应该会损坏吧
制服警在查各修车厂 但是没有车辆描述...
Uniform are asking local garages
but without a description of the
vehicle...
行了 继续
All right. Press on.
Oh, the results came through from
the range.
对了 你的射击成绩出来了
- 你从哪学的射击?
- 军队里
Where did you learn to shoot like
that? The Army, I suppose.
Thought you were in signals.
Mr Bright's very keen, in any event.
我以为你是通讯团呢 Bright先生表示非常关心
还问到了你下周的警长考试
Asked after your sergeant's exam
next week.
我跟他说你没问题 是没问题吧?
I told him you were on top of
things. You are, aren't you?
Well, I think so.
Think? You'd better be.
- 我觉得是
- 觉得? 你最好是
Don't want you treading water on
general duties another 12 months.
我可不想你再值一年班
Morning, sir. You're on this hit
and run, aren't you?
早上好 长官 那起交通逃逸是你负责的吧?
前台有个女人来报案 说她丈夫失踪
Woman come in to report her husband
missing.
A Mrs Coke Norris.
一位叫Coke Norris的太太
You got it?
知道了吗?
就说你考虑了一下 然后改变主意了
Tell 'em you've had a think
and changed your mind.
He was supposed to meet me.
Where?
- 他应该和我碰头的
- 哪里?
The station. I've been visiting
our daughter.
火车站 我去看女儿了
- 然后我等了又等
- Coke Norris太太...
I waited and waited.
Mrs Coke Norris...
他一般不这样
如果他说要去哪就一定会去的
If he says he's going to be
somewhere, then he invariably is.
Coke Norris太太
Mrs Coke Norris, um...
I'm afraid to say I may have some
very bad news for you.
我很遗憾 有些坏消息要告诉你
Last night I was called to attend
a road accident.
昨晚我被叫去处理一件交通事故
We'll need you to make
a formal identification, but...
我们还需要你去确认一下 但是...
I have strong reason to believe
that the man who lost his life was
your husband.
我有理由相信受害人就是你的丈夫
Oh...
还有谁需要我们通知吗? 你女儿?
Is there someone that we can notify?
Your daughter, perhaps?
对不起
Sorry.
Six, five, four,
六 五 四
三 二 一
three, two, one.
Ready or not, here I come.
好了没? 我来啦!
Alistair是个很受尊重的同事
Alistair was a much-valued
colleague,
held in great affection by all
who knew him.
所有认识他的人都很敬重他
Coke Norris太太告诉我
他昨天晚上是要出席一个会议的
Mrs Coke Norris told me that he was
due to attend a meeting here
yesterday evening.
是的 没错
Yes. Yes, indeed.
You weren't concerned
when he didn't arrive? No.
- 他没到场你不紧张吗?
- 不会
我是说 那只是个
I mean, it was just...
一般的学院管理事务会议
college business general
housekeeping.
How's she taken it?
Oh, as well as to be expected.
- 她怎么样?
- 跟预想的差不多
你知道他们结婚多久了?
Were they married long, do you know?
20 years or so.
20年了吧
Happily?
Oh... er...
- 很幸福?
- 呃...
是啊 是的
Yes. Yes.
There was the daughter, of course.
Audrey.
他们有个女儿 Audrey
我想那种事情肯定对任何婚姻都有影响
I imagine that kind of thing
must put a strain on any marriage.
There was an accident,
five or six years ago.
大概五六年前发生了一起事故
她被撞成了植物人
Left her a cabbage.
She's in a private hospital or
clinic in London.
她现在伦敦一家私人医院还是诊所里
我知道他们在那有个公寓
那样Millie可以常去看她
They keep a flat there, I believe,
so Millie can visit.
I'd like to take a look
at Professor Coke Norris's rooms.
我想看看Coke Norris教授的房间
His rooms?
他的房间?
Unless you've any objection.
除非你反对
No.
不
No, no. Of course not.
不 不会
我只是想不通他房间里
有什么会跟交通事故有关
I just can't see what bearing his
rooms might have on a traffic
accident.
It's just a question of us being
thorough in our inquiries, Master.
我们只想调查得彻底一些 院长先生
有什么可以帮你的吗?
Something I can do for you?
警员Morese 郡警局
DC Morse. City police.
Oh.
How do you do?
你好
Ian Kern. I'm a friend of
Alistair's.
我叫Ian Kern 是Alistair的朋友
I was.
曾经是
我去年借给他一本老的旅游指南
I lent him an old Baedeker's
last year.
南意的 对于我来说有私人意义 我不想它...
Southern Italy. It had some
sentimental value.
I didn't want it getting...
没事 你继续
No. Don't let me stop you.
谢谢
Thank you.
这实在太糟糕了
This is just awful.
太糟糕了
Awful.
找到那个司机了吗?
Is there any news as to the driver?
Not yet, I'm afraid.
抱歉 还没
What was he like?
他是个什么样的人?
Prickly.
敏感
慷慨
Generous.
善良
Kind.
非常善良
Mostly kind.
I shall miss him.
我会想念他的
What about Mrs Coke Norris?
What do you make to her?
那Coke Norris太太呢? 你怎么看她?
Millicent likes a project.
Millicent喜欢搞项目
Two years ago, we had starving
Africans.
两年前是非洲饥民
Last year, it was the plight of
the Red Indian.
去年是拯救北美印第安人
这个呢?
And this?
你看到了 老天真帮忙 她觉得我需要人照顾
You're looking at it, God help me.
She thinks I need mothering.
没处发挥母性了
你看到了 老天真帮忙 她觉得我需要人照顾
No outlet for the maternal instinct.
没处发挥母性了
隔天不是蛋糕就是炖肉
Every other day, it's cakes or
casseroles.
有人还得花钱才有的人照顾呢
Some might pay good money
to be cosseted like that.
Would they, though?
I don't doubt she means well,
是吗? 我知道她是好意
but if not for Alistair,
I'd have told her where to get off.
但如果不是因为Alistair 我会叫她离我远点
Did he have any enemies
that you can think of?
你知道他有什么敌人吗?
敌人?
Enemies?
天呐 没有
Good heavens, no.
Well, not enemies, I wouldn't have
said. What, then?
- 好吧 有是有 但我不会说那是敌人
- 那是什么?
Al had been a conchie, in the last
show. I mean, he did his bit on the
ambulances.
Al上次拒绝服兵役 我是说他在救护车服了役
But some people still held it
against him.
但是有些人还是拿这说事
找到了
Ah, Eureka.
如果没别的事 我就先走了
Well, unless there was anything
else, I'll leave you to your um...
Booth Hill? 你怎么问起这个来了?
Booth Hill? What makes you ask?
有个案子牵涉到了这个
It's come up in connection
with a case.
过去的18个月里 我们一直在报道此事
We've been reporting on it
for about the last 18 months.
With the Oxpens being cleared,
the council needs new housing stock.
Thanks.
现在农场都被拆了 镇上需要新的房屋 谢谢
The Housing Department's been in
negotiations with Baidley College
to acquire Booth Hill.
房产局一直在和Baidley学院协商要买Booth Hill
Baidley?
They own the land.
- Baidley学院?
- 他们是土地所有人
Not been very popular
with the Rural England brigade,
和英格兰乡村格格不入
but most objections have been dealt
with, one way or another.
但是在各种手段之下
大部分的反对意见都搞定了
A couple of tenant farmers
have been 'encouraged' to move on.
有些租农被"鼓励"重新开始
Strong arm stuff?
Nothing anyone will talk about.
- 暴力拆迁?
- 没人愿意提
Any idea where a Professor Coke
Norris might fit into this?
你知道为什么Coke Norris教授会牵涉其中么?
None. Why? Who is he?
不知道 怎么 他是谁
He was a classics don at Baidley.
Killed in a hit-and-run last night.
他是Baidley学院教古典文学的老师
昨晚死于在一起肇事逃逸
He'd been reading your article on
Booth Hill.
他一直在看你的Booth Hill报道
One or two new faces
hanging about recently.
最近有一两个生面孔出现
London types. Only, you didn't get
that off me, right?
伦敦来的 但是你还没把那个给我是吧?
你要是听到什么就告诉我
You hear anything more on that,
you let me know. Right?
Keep the change.
不用找了
Morse.
Morse
Albert是个好人 很可靠
Good man, Albert. Reliable.
10先令一次 最好靠得住
At ten bob a time, I expect he is.
Any copper's only as good
as the intelligence he gets.
一个好警察必须要会收集各种情报
你在Carshell都学了点什么?
What do they teach you?
我不记得在执法规程里有提到情报是要付费的
I don't remember anything in Judges'
Rules about paying for information.
那你又学到了一招不是?
Got something new to think about,
then, haven't you?
Maurie 生意怎样啊
Maurie. How's show business?
No business like it, Mr Thursday.
Can I get you a drink?
很好啊 Thursday先生 你要喝点什么吗?
We're not stopping,
thanks all the same.
我们不多待 多谢了
We just dropped by for a quick hello
with Charlie, if he's about.
我们就是过来跟Charlie打个招呼 要是他在的话
Charlie? No, no, he's uh...
Charlie? 不 他...
Oh. We've come all this way.
我们大老远来的
那他什么时候下班?
What time's he due, then?
你看 我听说他决定不做夜店的生意了
See, I heard he decided to call time
on the night club business.
好像是有人劝他退出
Word is somebody gave him what for.
Have I got that right?
对吗?
He's uh... signed the place over to
me. I'm running it now.
呃 他已经把这地方转让给我了
现在是我负责开店
你开玩笑吧 海螺我都不会给你去卖
You're pulling my leg. I wouldn't
leave you to run a whelk stall.
Sasha 来包烟
20 Guards, would you, Sasha?
Straight. As God's my judge.
Yeah, but he's not, though, is he?
- 真的 上帝做证
- 是啊 可上帝不在不是?
So what do you know about
this lorry-load of snout
knocked off last night?
昨晚有辆装着香烟的卡车被偷了
你知道点什么吗?
有事吗?
Is there something you want?
我什么也不知道
I don't know nothing about that.
别跟我耍花样 Maurie
Don't kid a kidder, Maurie.
You're a front man.
你可是打前站的
Near beer, blue jokes and totting up
the night's take. That's your forte.
啤酒 荤段子 合计一下当晚的收成 那是你的强项
So who's in the big chair now, eh?
那现在谁是老大?
Hello, Fred.
你好啊 Fred
Vic.
Vic
- 好久不见
- 可不是
Long time.
Ain't it just.
Keeping well? Family?
Mustn't grumble.
- 还好吧?
- 没啥可抱怨的
这算啥? Mile end那边对你来说太刺激了?
What's this? Things got a bit too
lively for you at Mile End?
不是 我退休不是吗?
Nah. Retired, ain't I?
谁都有那么一天的 Fred 你也不例外
All got it coming, Fred. Even you.
我就在这养老了
This place will see me out.
瞧啊
Well...
看看都放谁进来了
look what the dog brought in.
Do you remember my Vince?
你还记得我儿子Vince吧?
Fred Thursday. Look.
Fred Thursday 看看
天呐 你还干着呢
我还以为Carter那事之后他们让你退休了呢
Blimey, you still at it? I thought
they'd put you out to grass after
Carter.
至少道上是这么传的
That's the word in town, anyway.
Fred Thursday 被吓得回家找妈妈去了
Fred Thursday. Went milky and run
off crying to the sticks.
这又是谁?
Who's this, then?
- 你不用管他是谁
- Vince
Never you mind who it is.
Vince.
Kids, Fred. All piss and vinegar.
What can you do?
Fred 都是孩子 四处撒欢 你能咋办
- 跟我们当年一样
- 这么办
Same ourselves once.
Here's how it is.
你把你的人从我地盘上带走 我就什么都不计较
You round up your boys and get off
my patch and we'll leave it at that.
Might put the fear of God into
the locals, but this is me.
你这吓唬吓唬当地人还行 但现在是我
- 只一次警告
First and final.
Workhouse rules, Fred.
- 行有行规 Fred
Last man standing.
看谁撑到最后
So be it.
这么定了
你以为你已经找到了个像样的地方
You think you've found somewhere
decent,
没有腐败 可惜还是慢慢被渗透了
some place the rot hasn't got
to yet, but it creeps in.
They want to come that game here?
Over my dead body.
他们想在这儿折腾? 除非我死了
Carter是谁?
Who's Carter?
你离这远点
You stay away from this place.
And Vic Kasper. All right?
还有Vic Kasper 知道吗?
Just stick to that hit-and-run
and boning up for your sergeant's.
处理好你那起交通逃逸 好好准备你的警长考试
把这事交给我 明白?
Leave this to me. Understood?
There he is, sir.
他来了 长官
Ah, Morse.
Morse
你妹妹Joyce是吧
刚才你出去的时候给你打电话了
Your sister Joyce, is it,
called while you were out.
你父亲
It's your father.
他没事 就是吃得很少
He's all right. Just... taken poorly.
His heart, she said.
You're to telephone home.
她说是他的心脏问题 你最好打个电话回家
- 谢谢长官
- 如果你要请几天事假...
Thank you, sir. If you need some
compassionate leave...
I'm sure it won't come to that. Hope
for the best. That's the ticket.
- 应该不需要
- 希望 希望没事
Well...
Sir.
- 就这样...
- 长官
He suffers with angina.
Has done for years.
他有心绞痛 好多年了
- 我估计他们又小题大做了
- 你还是先打个电话吧
I'm sure they're making more of it
than there is. You won't know till
you talk to them.
If you're needed, you must go.
Sergeant Jakes at court.
- 如果他们需要你 你就得过去
- 但是Jakes警长上庭去了
我不想留你一个人处理所有的事情
I don't want to leave you a man down.
You let me worry about that.
这个还是留着我来操心吧
实际上 长官 确实有个人我觉得可以帮忙
Actually, sir, there is someone
I suppose you could look to.
- 我不会忘记这个的
- 只是暂代探员而已
I won't forget this. It's only
Acting Detective Constable.
- 不是永久职位啊
- 那也很好啊 伙计
It's not permanent.
Little acorns, matey.
See if you can get anywhere with
this car. Check the garages.
你去查查那部车
看看有什么线索 查查修车厂
没问题 希望你父亲... 你知道的
Righto. I hope your old man's uh...
Well, you know.
Joyce说她打了电话
Joyce said she'd telephoned.
Hello, Gwen.
- 你好 Gwen
I suppose you'd better come in.
- 你还是进来吧
你的房间全是家具
Your old room's full of lumber.
I'll be all right on the couch.
I've aired the bed in the spare.
- 我就在沙发上挤挤吧
- 我已经把客房准备好了
我不想招人说我们没好好待你
I won't have it said
we couldn't put you up.
- 你好啊陌生人
- 你好 Joycie
Hello, stranger.
Hello, Joycie.
你瘦了 他们没好好照顾你吗?
You've lost weight. They not looking
after you down there?
呃你知道的 他怎么样?
Oh, you know. How is he?
Sis?
妹妹?
其实你没必要过来的
There was no need
for you to come up.
我跟Joyce说了不要大惊小怪
I told Joyce not to fuss.
How do you feel?
你感觉怎么样
Just a bad turn. I'm right now.
就发作了一次 现在好多了
Can I get you anything?
你要点什么吗?
There's a three-year-old...
有个三岁的
Rowsby Woof,
小Rowsby Woof
每天2:15在Catterick表演
running in the 2:15 at Catterick.
You could put five bob on for us.
你可以给帮我们先给5先令
我本来想打电话的 但是她不让
I'd phone it through,
only she won't let me.
Penny for them.
想什么呢
他爸?
Dad?
工作
Work.
What work?
什么工作
Mickey Carter, if you must know.
Mickey Carter 如果你非要知道的话
Don't dwell, Fred.
别想太多 Fred
No.
没有
- 我以为你发誓不喝酒的
- 入错行了
I thought you'd taken the pledge.
Fell amongst thieves.
- 工作整的 我估计
- 是的
- 我以为你发誓不喝酒的
- 入错行了
Comes with the job, I suppose.
Probably.
干杯
Cheers.
Why did you go back... to Oxford?
你干嘛要回...牛津
Oh... A policeman goes
where he's sent.
呃 哪里需要警察就去哪里
我告诉老爸的时候 他就说了一句 箴言 26:11
(愚昧人行愚妄事 行了又行 就如狗转过来吃它所吐的)
When I told Pop, he just said,
'Proverbs 26:11'.
I thought... maybe...
我以为...或许...
Well...
呃...
I've many faults, God knows,
老天知道我有多少毛病
但是我绝对不会自虐的
but I try to draw the line at
masochism.
而且 一般来说应该是罪犯会回到犯罪现场
Besides, traditionally it's the
killer that returns to the scene of
the crime,
not the...
而不是...
Whatever I was.
我这样的
I'll telephone.
我会打电话的
There's no need, on my account.
没必要为了我
长途
Long distance.
Police still?
还在当警察
是啊
Yes.
I never liked the police.
我从来都不喜欢警察
- 我得走了
- 你要知道 他不是对你失望
I'd better be off. You're not,
you know, a disappointment.
他为你骄傲 他自己的方式
He's proud of you... in his way.
It's just...
只不过
you remind him of your mother.
你老让他想到你母亲
你会告诉他的情况的吧
Will you let me know how he is?
If I need to come back, or...
如果需要我回来 或者...
Since when do we do that?
我们什么时候这么亲密了
你看上去需要这个
You look like you could do with it.
- 谁?
- Vic Kasper 长官
Who?
Vic Kasper, sir.
他说他退休了 接手了Moonlight Rooms
Retired, he says.
Taken over the Moonlight Rooms.
- 洗白了
- 真的假的
Gone legit.
Any truth in it?
Faces like Vic Kasper
don't retire, sir.
像Vic Kasper这种人不会退休的 长官
I spoke to a colleague at the Yard.
我和苏格兰场的一个同事联系过
He says Kasper had recently become
persona non with Sid and Gerald
Fletcher.
他说最近Kasper跟Sid还有Gerald Fletcher不合
我和苏格兰场的一个同事联系过
You think he's come here
looking for a soft touch?
你认为他是来找人合伙的?
More likely he's come here to keep
breathing.
更像是来苟延残喘的
Oh. What are you doing out here?
It's perishing.
你在外面做什么? 冻死了
- 计划
- 真的?
Making plans.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
真的
You happy?
你开心吗?
Course.
Really? You like the house?
- 当然
- 真的? 你喜欢这房子吗
Yeah.
喜欢
我希望你开心
I want you to be happy.
有你我无所不能
You make me a king.
你和我 Cyn 永远一起
You and me, Cyn, all the way.
你个傻瓜
Oh, you stupid...
牛津38802
Oxford 38802.
Good afternoon.
This is Detective Constable Morse.
下午好 我是Morse探员 市警局
Could you give me your address,
please? What do you want it for?
- 你那边地址是什么?
- 地址 你要地址干嘛?
I'm trying to trace someone at this
number with the initials 'JV'.
我想找一位缩写为JV的人
Operations room, could you get me
a reverse trace on Oxford 38802?
总机室 你能反追踪一下牛津38802这个号码吗
哎 伙计 没想到你这么快就回来了
Hello, matey.
Wasn't expecting you back so soon.
All...?
一切都...?
都好
Yeah, fine.
Any luck with the garages?
修车厂查得咋样了
I did a ring around of pretty much
every garage in the book, actually.
我几乎把电话本里的修车厂都排查了一遍
Got a list of all vehicles booked in
for body repairs since it happened.
把事故发生以来所有送修的车都列了表
很长很多 不过还是有收获的
Quite a long list, as it turns out,
but it paid dividends.
昨天有一辆宾利送到了Kidlington的一个修车厂
There was a Bentley booked in
at a dealership in Kidlington
yesterday.
挡风玻璃坏了
Cracked windscreen.
车主是叫Jolyon Frobisher
Owner, Mr Jolyon Frobisher.
The Master at Baidley?
Hm.
Baidley学院的院长? 是
A piece of cake,
this detecting lark.
这侦探的活还真是简单
Don't know what you make all that
fuss about.
不知道你都大惊小怪些什么
Frobisher博士
Dr Frobisher.
Dorothea Frazil, Oxford Mail.
Dorothea Frazil 牛津邮报
我想问问 你作为Baidley院长
对我们最近有关
I wondered if, as Master of Baidley,
you had any comment to make
Booth Hill的文章 有什么看法
in response to our recent article
on Booth Hill.
On, the record, obviously,
I'm very concerned by such
allegations.
官方的说 我对这些指控很关心
And off the record, Dr Frobisher?
那非官方的呢 Frobisher博士?
I think those who make
irresponsible allegations in print
我认为那些在报纸上作出不负责任指控的人
要非常小心了
should take very great care.
Thursday先生 我不能啊
你知道的 可不只是我的命
I can't, Mr Thursday. You know that.
It's more than my life.
Fair enough, Maurie. Better get him
back, then, Sergeant Jakes.
行啊 Maurie
那送他回去吧 Jakes警长
要是被Kasper看到我们
送他去Moonlight Rooms可不太好啊 长官
It won't look good if Kasper sees us
dropping him off outside the
Moonlight Rooms.
会有人以为他去告密了 管不住自己的嘴巴
Someone might take him for a grass
and think he's been running his
mouth
off?
But I ain't.
但是我没有啊
Look, Vic came in, as a sleeping
partner, with Charlie, about two
years ago.
听着 两年前 Vic作为Charlie的匿名合伙人加入
我就知道这些
That's all I know.
Charlie was happy with that?
You don't say no to Vic Kasper.
- Charlie乐意?
- 你没法对Vic Kasper说不
下车吧 你可以搭公车回去
Go on, then.
You can get the bus back.
Millie 嗨
Oh. Millie. Hello.
我还以为门房搞错了
I thought the porter must have it
wrong.
The Master insisted.
院长坚持的
How are you?
你怎么样
Rather at sixes and sevens,
I'm afraid.
乱七八糟的我感觉
想把葬礼搞好点 但是我估计我搞得一团糟
Trying to organise the funeral but I
imagine I'm making a hash of it.
Millie
Oh, Millie.
It really is too bad.
那真是太糟糕了
我真的不忍心看你这样
I can't bear to see you like this.
我没事 真的
Oh, I'm all right. Really.
Nonsense. You've looked after me
in so many ways.
乱讲 你照顾了我这么多
All those wonderful meals you
prepared.
做了那么多好吃的饭菜
So, listen, I'm going to come over
and help tidy Al's things.
听着 我会过去帮忙整理Al的东西
- 他的东西?
- 论文
His things?
His papers.
文章之类的
Essays.
还有其他需要处理的东西
Whatever else needs taking care of.
如果他跟我一样
说不定还有一堆学校图书馆的书要还
If he was anything like me, there
may well be books from the college
library need returning.
So, how's that sound?
那样如何
Really?
那真是太好了
Oh... Oh, that would be most
terribly kind.
没关系
Not at all.
Many hands, eh?
Two heads better than one.
两个人总强过一个人
Morse探员 郡警局
DC Morse. City police.
我一个小时前给这里打过电话
I spoke to someone on the telephone
here, an hour ago.
- 是你接的吗 贵姓?
- Judy Vallens
Would that have been you, Miss...?
Vallens. Judy.
不是我 我刚回来20分钟
Uh, no. I've only been in
about 20 minutes.
Any idea why Professor Coke Norris
might have your initials and
telephone number
那你知道为什么Coke Norris教授的火柴盒上
written in a matchbook,
Miss Vallens?
写着你的名字缩写和电话 Vallens小姐
None.
不知道
我偶尔会去他的讲座 就这样
I see him every now and then at
lectures. But that's it.
你在哪所学院读书
You're a student at which college?
Matilda学院
I'm a Matilda-beast. Lady Matilda's.
Oh.
那火柴盒呢 你见过吗
What about the matchbook?
Do you recognise that?
你确定?
You sure about that?
那些...
Those...
Uh... yes.
呃 没错
I'm sorry. That would be
my flatmate, Georgina Bannard.
不好意思 那是我室友Georgina Bannard的
她从工作的地方带回来的
She gets them from work.
- 她在哪工作?
- Broad街上的一家具乐部
Where's that?
Some club off the Broad.
The Moonlight Rooms.
Mm.
- Moonlight Rooms
- 嗯
What does she do there?
Cigarette girl.
- 她在那做什么
- 她是卖烟的
Is she at home?
她在家吗?
我想跟她谈谈
I'd like to speak with her.
我从学院回来的时候
她所有的东西都不见了
When I got back from college,
all her stuff was gone.
Have you roomed together long?
你们合租多久了
八九个月
Eight or nine months.
Might she have a boyfriend
she's gone to?
她会不会去男朋友那住?
Nobody steady, I don't think.
What about family?
- 没什么固定男朋友
- 家人呢
West Country somewhere?
好像是西南部什么地方
你会不会刚好有她的照片
You wouldn't have a photograph,
by any chance?
No. Why would I?
没有 我怎么会有
We're not close.
我们没那么亲近
You seem very nervous,
if you don't mind my saying so.
你看上去很紧张
如果你不介意我这么说的话
你...在担心什么吗?
Is... Is there something worrying
you?
Besides coming home to find that
Gina's cleared out and landed me
with the rent
除了我回来就发现Gina卷铺盖走人
留我一个人交房租
然后没过20分钟你就来了的话
and you showing up 20 minutes later?
那个 如果...
Well, if...
If she does happen to get in touch,
could you ask her to call me?
如果她跟你联系了 你能请她给我打个电话吗?
She's not in any trouble. I'd just...
I'd just like to speak with her.
她没惹上什么麻烦
我只是...我只是想问她点事情
Did your husband ever talk about
a Judy Vallens?
你先生提过一个名叫Judy Vallens的女子吗?
She's an undergrad
at Lady Matilda's.
她是Matilda女子学院的
No.
没有
那Georgina Bannard呢
How about Georgina Bannard?
如果你以为我先生和这些女学生之间
If you entertain any suspicion of
impropriety between my husband and
these young women,
有任何不检点的关系的话
I believe I can set your mind
at rest.
我相信我可以解答你这个疑问
After Audrey's accident...
Audrey的事故之后
Oh, how to put it.
Alistair lost all interest in, and,
indeed, facility for physical
intimacy.
我该怎么说呢
Completely.
Alistair对所有的亲密行为都没兴趣 也没能力
He used to ride to hounds, you see.
彻底的
他以前总喜欢去骑马打猎
When Audrey was 12, he took her out
for the Alvescot hunt.
Audrey12岁的时候 他带她去Alvescot打猎
Meant to be her blooding.
Only, there was...
等于是她的第一次体验
可是
Alistair said that a snipe broke
cover right in front of her mount
and she was thrown and...
Alistair说那有只鸟刚好从她的马前飞过去
她被甩下马然后...
Al felt himself responsible,
you see.
Al觉得他自己有责任
He wasn't, of course, but...
Oh.
当然他没有 但是...
我听说她在一家诊所 在伦敦
She's in some sort of clinic,
I understand. In London.
她需要长时间的专家护理
She needs constant specialist care.
那你先生提起过Booth Hill吗 Coke Norris太太
Did your husband ever mention
Booth Hill, Mrs Coke Norris?
嗯 过去一年里 他除了这个几乎没说别的
Well, for the past year or so,
he talked of little else.
真的? 为什么? 他为什么这么感兴趣?
Really? Why? What was his interest?
Booth Hill was originally
owned by Alistair's family.
Booth Hill原本是Alistair家族的
一战以后他们就把它送给了Baidley学院
They gifted it to Baidley College
after the Great War...
as a way of avoiding death duties.
为了免交遗产税
Land rich, cash poor.
土地很多 但是资金很少
So where did he stand
on this proposed development?
那他对这个开发提案是什么态度
他觉得这个有违于当初送土地的初衷
He felt it went against the spirit
of the gift.
Not that anyone seemed to care
very much.
不过并不是所有人都重视
Except for Ian, of course.
Ian?
- 当然除了Ian
- Ian?
- Kern博士
- 啊
Dr Kern.
Ah.
Everyone else was more concerned
with what they were going to make
out of it personally.
其他所有人都更关心他们个人能从中得什么利
所有的资深成员都能有笔不小的意外之财
All the senior fellows stand to gain
a considerable windfall.
Including your husband?
Alistair wouldn't have taken it.
- 包括你丈夫
- Alistair不会接受
有悖他的原则
As a point of principle.
Not that I imagine Jolyon Frobisher
will feel such an offer need be made
now.
我估计现在Jolyon Frobisher
倒是可以省掉他那份了
The sale was formally approved,
I understand,
据我所知 出售方案已经在会上正式通过了
at a meeting the evening
Professor Coke Norris died.
就在Coke Norris教授死的那天晚上
Mm.
那和你跟我说的一般学院事务可是完全两回事
That's more at stake than the general
housekeeping you led me to believe.
I said it was college business.
Which it is.
我说那是学院事务 那确实是
要是教授反对的话 是不是就泡汤了?
Might the professor have carried the
day if he'd spoken against?
他不会反对的
He would not.
这块土地已经归学院所有近50年了
The land has been in college
ownership for nearly 50 years.
It's ours to dispose of
as we think best.
应该由我们自己来决定到底怎么处理
Why? Is the college short of funds?
为什么? 学院缺少资金吗
Management of the land has been
a constant drain on resources.
管理这么大一片土地很耗费资源
The decision was as much about
what the college stood to save by
letting it go
这个决定是衡量了学院在保留土地还是出售上
所需花费的资源后做出的
as about what it might gain.
Your vehicle's been booked in the
garage with a broken windscreen.
你的车最近因为挡风玻璃坏了去送修了
How did that happen? I came out
one morning and there it was.
- 那是怎么回事?
- 我有天早上出门的时候就那样了
肯定有人故意的 或者哪个本科生喝醉了
Vandals, I suppose,
or some drunken undergraduate prank.
或者是你的哪个租户
Or some of your late tenant farmers
想表达一下被赶离他们的土地的不满
expressing their displeasure
at being driven off their land?
'Their' land?
他们的土地?
你算什么 社会主义者
What are you? Some sort of
socialist?
Booth Hill是我们的土地 至少现在是
Booth Hill is our land,
for the moment.
How did you know about my car?
你怎么知道我的车的
调查撞人逃逸案的时候 我们会调查所有修车厂里
When investigating a hit-and-run,
it's procedure to compile a list
of all vehicles booked in for
bodywork or windscreen repairs post
facto.
修理车身或挡风玻璃的事后车辆 这是程序
Oh, post facto, indeed.
事后 的确
After the fact.
I know what it means.
- 事件发生后
- 我知道那什么意思
那你不反对我同事检查你的车吧
Then you'll have no objection to one
of my colleagues taking a look at
your vehicle.
None.
不反对
Unfortunately, it's presently
on loan to my brother.
不过不幸的是 我把车借给我弟弟了
那我在哪里能找到他
Where might I find your brother?
On the Continent somewhere.
在大陆的什么地方吧
He's decided to drive down
to Monte for a few weeks.
他决定开车去Monte玩几个星期
Of course, as soon as he returns,
I'll let you know.
当然他一回来 我会通知你的
我很期待
I'll look forward to it.
Coke Norris是准备在会议上
反对Booth Hill出售提案的
Coke Norris was meant to speak
against the sale of this Booth Hill.
Only, he was killed by a hit-and-run
driver on the way in.
可是在去的路上被撞死了
The ayes carried the day.
That the Moonlight Room's motif?
- 于是那天就通过了
- 这是Moonlight Room的东西是吧?
I'm hoping they might shed some
light on this Georgina Bannard.
是的 我想找他们问问
有关Georgina Bannard的消息
- 我说过我不想你跟他们打交道
- 为什么
I don't want you getting involved
with them. Why?
没有为什么
Because Y's not a Z.
Do you mean because of Carter?
是因为Carter?
那你不反对我去市政厅吧?
Well, do you have any objection
to me going to the Town Hall?
I've a meeting with Mark Carlisle,
senior planning officer.
我要去见Mark Carlisle 高级规划师
你想找谁找谁 就是离Vic Kasper远点
Talk to whoever you want.
Just keep away from Vic Kasper.
对了 你家里怎么样 你父亲好些了?
Anyway, how'd you make out at home?
Your father on the mend?
嗯 看上去是
Yeah. Seems to be.
你那是什么 Lager?
What's that, then?
Lager beer, is it?
Double diamond 很神奇
Double Diamond. Works wonders.
神奇的是竟然有人买这个
The wonder is anyone buys the stuff.
Pour me one while you're there.
Pour it yourself.
- 顺便帮我倒一杯
- 自己倒
You'd pour him one.
你会给他倒的
Yeah, I would.
是的我会
他说啥了
Has he said anything?
He thinks you're gonna land him
in it.
他认为你会给他惹麻烦
那个警察在问Maurie那一卡车香烟的事情
That copper was talking to Maurie
about a lorry-load of smokes.
If he wanted to retire, he should
have bought a bungalow and moved
to Margate.
他如果真的想退休
他就该去买座小别墅搬去Margate
It's disgusting how he's carrying
on. He's earned it.
- 他这么弄下去可真恶心
- 那是他应得的
He's gone soft. He's more of a man
than you'll ever be.
- 他越来越服软了
- 你永远都做不到像他那么男人
Thorpie on the phone, Vin.
Vin 你的电话 是Thorpie
别给他添乱 那是他想要的
Don't mess it up for him.
It's what he wants.
那我想要的呢
What about what I want?
What do you want, Vince?
那你想要什么 Vince
看来Baidley学院能赚一大笔钱
Baidley stand to make quite a lot of
money, I'd imagine.
赔偿金是很客观 但是我们的出发点是社会良知
The recompense is proportionate,
but our impulse is one of social
conscience.
Have you seen some of the housing
at the Oxpens?
你见过那边农场的房子吗
- 是啊 见过
Oh, yes, indeed.
- 那你肯定知道那地方就是个垃圾场
Then you know the place is a midden.
People need somewhere decent
to live.
人们需要有个好的地方生活
有热水 室内有厕所
Hot water. Indoor plumbing.
这个新的开发计划会采光很好 很干净 又通风
This new development will be light,
clean, airy.
你应该看过报纸了吧
You've seen the papers, presumably?
The Mail. The story about the tenant
farmers being driven off the land.
邮报 有关租户被赶离土地的报道
I hope you're not suggesting the
council would have anything to do
with such a thing.
我希望你不是暗示地方议会和那个有关系
有人非常想让他们搬走
Someone was very keen
to have them off the land.
如果你相信他们说的话
If they're to be believed.
Money in the air.
有利可图
They could just be laying
the groundwork to bring a suit.
他们有可能就那么躺在地基上 就为了能打官司
For what?
Compensation.
- 为什么
- 赔偿金
Loss of earnings. Who knows?
失去生活来源 谁知道呢
普通的乡村人家
Simple everyday country folk?
I wouldn't trust half of them
as far as I could spit.
能有一半可信就不错了
Kids haven't seen it?
Think I'm stupid?
- 孩子们没看到吧
- 你以为我傻吗
Who sent it?
谁送来的?
Is that why you were on about Mickey
Carter the other night?
这就是为什么你那天晚上想Mickey Carter的事情吗?
I thought we left all this behind.
我以为那件事情已经过去了
Evening, Officer.
晚上好 警官
有什么需要帮忙的吗
What can I get you?
我在找一个名叫Georgina Bannard的女孩
I'm looking for a Georgina Bannard.
她在这里卖烟
I believe she's a cigarette girl.
想不起来了 她们来来去去的
Don't ring a bell. They come and go.
Stick around, enjoy the show.
留下来吧 看看表演
他要点什么都算在我账上
Anything he wants, on the house.
Ladies and gentlemen, would you
please put your hands together
女士们先生们 请鼓掌
and give a Moonlight Rooms welcome
热烈欢迎Lila Pilgrim小姐
光临Moonlight Rooms
to Miss Lila Pilgrim.
# Darlin', don't you go
# Darlin', don't you go near me
with your blues
# I need some rock and roll
# Save my soul
# Darlin', don't be mean
# If you stay with me,
let you be my king
# I wanna be your queen
# Darlin', don't you go
# Darlin', don't you go near me
with your blues
# I need some rock and...
# Rock and ro-o-oll... #
嘿 你在干嘛?
Hey! What's your game?
Oh.
- 你没看到我在换衣服吗
- 我很抱歉 我...
Can't you see a girl's getting
changed? I'm sorry. I...
just wanted to ask if any of you
know a girl called Georgina Bannard.
只是想问问你们是不是认识
一个叫Georgina Bannard的姑娘
Lost something?
丢东西了吗?
演员专用 你不识字吗?
Artistes only. Can't you read?
No customers back here.
顾客禁止入内
- 要我跟你说两遍吗?
- 没事 Vince
Want me to tell you twice?
It's all right, Vince.
我来 你要进来吗?
I've got it.
Do you want to come through?
真抱歉 小姐
I'm sorry, miss.
无耻
Cheeky.
- 酒?
- 不用了 谢谢 你是?
Drink?
Er, no, thank you, Miss...
Cynthia Riley 叫我Cyn就好了
Riley. Cynthia. Call me Cyn.
那你在这里是做什么的 Riley小姐
So, where do you fit into this
setup, Miss Riley?
- 女主持
- 明白了
Hostess.
I see.
I doubt it.
真的吗?
Maurie说你在找什么
Maurie said you were looking for
something.
That's right. Georgina Bannard.
She works here as a cigarette girl.
是啊 Georgina Bannard 她在这卖烟
谁说的?
Says who?
Well, does she or doesn't she?
那她是不是在这卖烟呢?
Not here, ducky.
不在这 亲爱的
你看上去人挺好的 但是...
Look, you seem like a nice bloke,
but um...
这里要是有警察的话客人们会很紧张 所以...
having coppers about
makes the clientele jumpy, so...
whatever you're about...
不管你想做什么
please just drop it. Walk away.
请放弃吧 离开这里
Or what?
不然呢?
# ..rushed to his face
and with the make-up, it burns
# A smile so wide
that you could sit there and hide
# From the lights on the stage
# As they cried his name
# Cos he has the answer
# Tangled
# But there's nobody laughing when
# He gets home
# You have to be pretty lonely
# When the spotlight's your home
# Cos he is the answer
# Tangled
# Just an exotic-looking creature
# In a glass container
# You could watch him, watch him
# Watch him scratch his leg
# Watch him when he sleeps, yeah
# You can watch him till his death #
- 我想这是你的
- 你在玩什么把戏?
Yours, I believe.
What's your game?
Vince.
You send this to my home? My home!
- Vince
- 你送这个去我家? 我家!
Not me, Fred. You got it all wrong.
不是我 Fred 你搞错了
Watch it, coming in here,
throwing your weight about.
放开我 你跑这来在这耀武扬威
你会跟你的手下Carter一样下场的
You'll go the same way
as your boy Carter.
- 你说什么?
- 长官
What did you say?
Sir.
You heard.
你听到了
I don't think I did. Come out from
behind your mates and tell me again.
我没听到 你为什么不站出来再说一遍
爸
Dad.
Get out now. Morse, see her back.
出去 Morse 送她回去
- 刚才我们说到哪了?
- 坐下来 孩子
Now, where were we?
Sit down, boy.
- 你就让他这么着?
- 坐下来
You gonna let him come in like that?
Sit down.
You come near my family again,
you'll be needing a wreath, not me.
你敢再靠近我家人 要花圈的就是你了
Who's there?
谁在那?
你不会说吧?
You won't say anything?
Peter的事
About Peter.
Please. It's not easy meeting
blokes. With Dad.
拜托 有这样的爸 想认识男孩子可不容易
没人...天呐 等一下
No one's... Oh, God. Wait a minute.
Oh.
Well, he can't dance.
I know that much.
他不会跳舞 至少我知道了这个
Nobody's ever good enough.
都没人够好过
I'm sure he's just got your best
interests at heart.
我想他是为了你好
那倒是实话
That's very square.
我以为如果是个警察的话就没事了
I thought it would be all right
with a copper.
Well, there are coppers and there
are coppers.
警察也分好多种
那你是哪种?
And what sort are you?
I'm the sort that see young ladies
safely home.
我是那种会把年轻的女士安全送到家的
进去吧 我等你进门
Go on. I'll wait till you get
inside.
Don't say anything, will you?
什么都别说好吗?
谢谢
Thanks.
晚安
Good night.
Night.
晚安
她在哪?
Where is she?
- 他们没...?
- 没 只是吓唬吓唬她
They didn't...?
No. Just put the frighteners on.
- 现在每个人都是评论家
Everyone's a critic.
Any idea what was behind it?
- 知道谁干的吗?
Oh, they were quite specific.
他们说得很详细
I'm to lay off any further stories
about Booth Hill
if I know what's good for me.
如果我知道好歹 就不会再继续报道Booth Hill
Which, alas, was a lesson
I never took to.
可惜啊 那是我永远也学不会的教训
我昨天把Baidley院长问得很难堪
I put the Master of Baidley
rather on the spot yesterday.
He marked my dance card
in no uncertain terms.
他要表达的意思再明显不过了
Frobisher恐吓你了
Frobisher threatened you?
A bit heavy-handed for academics.
对于学院派来说有点暴力了
我不觉得他们会弄脏自己的手
I don't expect they did
their own dirty work.
All I've managed to glean, there
seems to be some vague London
connection.
我打探到的消息 好像是他们和伦敦有些关系
- 伦敦
- 我想他们提到了Fletcher这个名字
London?
I've picked up the name Fletcher.
- 一两次 好像是Sid 如果有用的话
- 可能
Sid, maybe, if that means anything.
It might.
- 有没有看到是谁干的
- 太黑了
Get a decent look at whoever it was?
It was dark.
But there were two of them.
但是有两个人
我已经跟Strange警员描述过了
I've given a description to
Constable Strange.
Unless there was anything else...
如果没别的事的话
I've got a leader to write.
我有篇稿子要赶
你否认你威胁过她?
You deny you threatened her?
Young man, that's a grossly
impertinent question.
年轻人 这个问题太鲁莽了
你再对我这么高人一等的说话
Condescend to me, Master,
and I'll frogmarch you
across that quad,
我就直接手铐铐着你走过那个院子
down the high and into Cowley police
station, in handcuffs.
沿着主街 一直到Cowley警局
Do you understand?
你听明白了吗?
你威胁过她吗?
Did you threaten her?
我完全否认这个指控
I refute the allegation utterly.
As I do her previous farrago of
printed untruths
and half-baked innuendo.
我同样否认她之前在报上
那些歪曲事实含沙射影的报道
你想否认就否认吧
Refute all you please.
如果被我发现你和昨晚的事情有任何关系
If I find out you had anything to do
with what happened last night,
我会让你没好日子过的
I'll bring the roof down
on your head.
有人投诉了
A complaint has been made,
Baidley学院的院长投诉Morse
by the Master of Baidley College,
about Morse.
大致是说Morse指控他在背后操纵了
昨晚在邮报发生的事情
More or less accused him of being
behind this incident at the Mail.
邮报一直在调查
The paper's been investigating links
Booth Hill和伦敦黑社会Fletcher兄弟会之间的联系
between Booth Hill and certain
figures in the London underworld
the Fletchers.
但不是你一直担心的Kasper
But not this Kasper character
you're so keen on.
众所周知Vic Kasper和Fletchers兄弟有关系
Vic Kasper and the Fletchers
are known associates.
我理解的是以前有关系
Former known associates,
as I understand it.
The Chief Constable doesn't want
the Master troubled again.
局长不希望我们再去骚扰院长
Booth Hill开发计划是地方房屋计划的一部分
The development of Booth Hill is
an integral part of the council's
housing scheme.
Frobisher complains to the Mayor,
Frobisher跟市长抱怨
市长再跟局长抱怨
the Mayor complains
to the Chief Constable...
- 谋杀不能挡住发财的路
- 谋杀?
Can't let murder stand in the way of
profit. Murder?
没有任何证据显示Coke Norris教授的死
Nothing suggests that what happened
to Professor Coke Norris
was anything more than a tragic
accident.
不是个意外的悲剧
I don't want this animus
between Kasper and yourself
我不希望你和Kasper之间的怨怼
演变成私人恩怨
turning into some kind of
private vendetta.
This is not the Wild West.
I know my duty.
- 这里是牛津 不是西部
- 我知道我的职责 长官
See you remember it.
I'm thinking of you, Thursday.
你最好记住这一点 我是为你好 Thursday
我见过很多好警官因为个人纠纷而失足
I've seen too many a good officer
lose his way over some personal
feud.
相信我 那种事情从来都没好结果
Believe me, such things
never end well.
Sorry to interrupt, sir, but we've
got a report of a young woman's body
being found.
很抱歉打断一下 长官
有人报案发现一具年轻女子的尸体
Looks like foul play.
好像是谋杀
- 谁发现的尸体
- 一对恋人 长官
Who found the body?
A courting couple, sir.
Quite a popular locale for it.
Even in this weather?
- 很多人都来这约会
- 这么冷的天?
血气旺盛啊兄弟
When the blood's up, matey.
Big with the local toms, too, sir.
For what it's worth.
还有很多怀春雄猫在此 长官 你听着就好
知道她是谁吗?
Anything to say who she was?
这是她口袋里所有的东西了
This is all she had in her pocket,
I'm afraid.
Back of the head. Point blank.
后脑勺 近距离
Couple of days ago by the look of
things. Couple of days?
- 看起来死了两三天了
- 两三天
你确定吗? 确定? 如果这是叫Bannard的姑娘的话
她室友说昨天还见过她
Sure? Sure? If it is this Bannard
girl, her flatmate said she saw her
yesterday.
Put it this way, Morse.
这么说吧 Morse
Either I'm a Home Office pathologist
of some years standing,
要么我这个工作多年的内政部法医
who's suddenly taken leave of
his senses, or she's a liar.
突然失心疯了 要么她在撒谎
老实说 我知道该把赌注押在哪
Frankly, I know where I'd put
my sixpence.
这是唯一一张我和Georgina的照片
It's the only photograph
I have of us, of Georgina.
I found it after Constable Morse had
left. It had fallen down the back of
the fridge.
Morse警员走了之后我找到了
它掉到了冰箱后面
It's not her... is it?
那不是她吧?
我很抱歉 Vallens小姐
I'm very sorry, Miss Vallens.
Oh, my God.
天呐
So when did you last see her?
那你最后一次见到她是什么时候?
She was still working at the
Moonlight Rooms, wasn't she?
她还在Moonlight Rooms上班是吗?
You're like a bad penny, Fred.
你还真是阴魂不散啊 Fred
看来你带了朋友来 人多安全是吧
I see you've brought your friends.
Safety in numbers, eh?
去倒杯茶 还是你想来点酒?
Get a brew on.
Or do you want a man's drink?
You know this girl?
你认识这个女子吗?
- 我应该认识吗?
- 她在Moonlight Rooms工作
Should I?
She worked at the Moonlight Rooms.
I don't get involved in the staff.
That's Cyn's side.
我不处理员工事务 那是Cyn管的
Looker, though.
很好看倒是真的
你跟Coke Norris这事有关吗 Vic?
You involved in this business
with Coke Norris, Vic?
Coke Norris? 那是谁?
Coke Norris? What's that?
- 这是做什么
- 那天晚上我问你是否认识这姑娘
What's this all about? The girl I
asked you about the other night.
Georgina Bannard.
Georgina Bannard
How long had she worked at the club?
她在俱乐部做了多久?
我不知道 我来的时候她就已经在这了
I don't know. She was there
when I arrived.
她工作没什么问题 她是个勤快的小姑娘
I had no trouble with her.
She was a good little worker.
Well, she's a dead little worker
now.
她现在是个死了的勤快的小姑娘
今天早上发现了她的尸体
They found her body this morning.
后脑勺中了一枪
Somebody had put a bullet
in the back of her skull.
That's too bad.
那太糟糕了
- 是啊
- 你说她叫什么?
Yeah.
What did you say her name was?
- Georgina Bannard
- 不是
Georgina Bannard.
No.
她用的是另外一个名字
She called herself something else.
Judy. That was it.
Judy 对 是这个名字
Yeah. Judy Vallens.
是Judy Vallens
If it's any use.
如果对你有用的话
She used different names,
depending how the mood took her.
她会用不同的名字 看心情
The mood? She got in with people
when she was younger.
- 心情
- 她小时候和人一起的时候被抓过
占她便宜的人
People who took advantage.
男人 你明白吧 最后留了案底
Men. You know?
Ended up with a record.
她是个妓女?
She was a known prostitute?
那她和Coke Norris教授有性的关系?
Was she involved with Professor Coke
Norris in that capacity?
前阵子 她被派去Bayswater的一条街上去和某个人碰面
A while ago, she was sent to meet
this man in a mews in Bayswater.
- 谁派她去的
- 她同事什么的
Sent by whom?
Someone from where she worked.
她要从Baidley学院的一个文件架上拿串钥匙
She had to collect a key
from a cubbyhole at Baidley.
- 谁的
- 院长的
Whose cubbyhole?
The Master's.
- Frobisher的
- 你是怎么知道
Frobisher's?
How did you know that?
Because I was with her
when she picked it up.
因为她去拿钥匙的时候我和她一起
为什么
How was that?
You were...
你们
关系不一般 是吗?
particular friends, would it be?
You wouldn't be the first to have
their head turned by a working girl.
你不是第一个被作女改变观念的人
I went with her to London, I kept
out of the way.
我跟她去了伦敦 但是我躲了起来
那个男的来了
And the man arrived.
我认出他是市政厅的
It turned out that he was to do with
the Town Hall.
他喝多了然后就开始讲
He'd had a lot to drink and he'd
started talking...
well, bragging about some deal
that the council had going.
吹嘘地方委员会在做的一些交易
Booth Hill?
Booth Hill
他说他已经准备好付钱了
He said that he stood to make
a packet,
only there was a don at the college
trying to stop it going through.
但是学院里有个老师一直在阻止
- Coke Norris教授
- 你知道吗 那就是很奇怪我又不明白的地方
Professor Coke Norris.
That was the weird thing.
You see, it was Coke Norris's flat
that we were in.
要知道 当时我们就在Coke Norris的公寓里
How could you know that?
There were photos there...
- 你怎么知道?
- 那里有很多照片
他和他妻子还有女儿
of him and his wife
and their daughter.
但是从这个人说话的方式来看
But from the way that this man was
talking...
听起来好像不喜欢教授 非常的不喜欢
it sounded as if he had it in for
the Professor, I mean, really had it
in.
You tried to warn Coke Norris?
你想警告Coke Norris
You wrote your number down on a
matchbook and slipped it to him,
asked him to call. Did he?
你把你的号码写在火柴盒上然后悄悄放到
他的口袋里 要他打电话给你 他联系了你吗?
他从学院回家的路上来了一次我们家
He dropped by our flat
on the way home from college
the day that he got knocked down.
就在他被撞的那天
我告诉他我听到的东西
I told him what I'd heard.
那个市政厅的人 他叫什么
This man from the Town Hall...
did he have a name?
Carlisle.
Carlisle
Sexual favours?
That's a scandalous allegation.
色情交易? 那是诽谤
In return for what?
有什么好处
确保Booth Hill的收购计划不出任何差错
Making sure the purchase of Booth
Hill from Baidley goes through
without a hitch.
还有建筑合同中标给你想要的人
And seeing the construction contract
is awarded to the right bidder.
那那个和我有交易的女孩是谁
Who is she, this girl I'm supposed
to have been carrying on with?
You'd have known her as
Judy Vallens.
她告诉你的名字应该是Judy Vallens
Her real name is Georgina Bannard.
她的真名是Georgina Bannard
You met her in a flat in Bayswater
a couple of months ago.
几个月前你在Bayswater的一间公寓里见过她
今天早上我们发现了她的尸体
We found her body this morning.
她后脑中枪
She'd been shot
in the back of the head.
The people you've got involved with
are very dangerous individuals,
Mr Carlisle.
你打交道的都是些危险人物 Carlisle先生
I'd urge you to cooperate with
our enquiries. We can protect you.
我劝你和我们合作 我们可以保护你
我不需要保护
I don't need protecting.
我没做错什么
I've done nothing wrong.
Unless you're here to charge me with
something, I've nothing else to say.
除非你们是来起诉我的 否则我无话可说
I'd think about that, if I were you.
如果我是你 我会好好想想的
在局子里呆一段时间总好过永远地躺在棺材里
A short spell inside's better than
eternity in a wooden box.
You know where to reach us
if you change your mind.
你要是改变了主意 你知道哪里可以找到我们
This flat of yours in London,
Mrs Coke Norris.
Coke Norris太太 你们在伦敦的那间公寓
我想让Morse警员去看看 如果你不反对的话
Unless you've any objection,
I'd like to send Constable Morse
to take a look.
当然不了
No, of course not.
但是Alistair好久没去了
But Alistair hasn't been there in
weeks.
是吗? 他上次是什么时候去的
No? When was he last there?
We went to the proms in September.
我们9月一起去的音乐会
是吗? 什么节目?
Really? What was the programme?
A Haffner and Mahler 4.
Haffner和马勒第4交响曲
这重要吗?
Is it important?
没有 我一直想去 但都没去成
Only in so far as I wanted to go...
but without success.
Well, you missed out.
It was quite wonderful.
你错过了 非常好
我们周末就在那 去看Audrey
We stayed up for the weekend,
saw Audrey,
周一早上第一班火车回来的
caught the first train back
early on Monday morning.
How often do you visit your
daughter? Every week, if I can.
- 你多久去看你女儿一次
- 每周 如果我可以
- 每周同一天还是不同的日子
- 同一天
On the same day each week or
different days? The same day.
那如果有人注意你们生活的话
So someone watching your movements
就会猜到你丈夫什么时候会独自一人
might be able to guess
when your husband might be alone?
我想应该是
I suppose they could, yes.
Carter太太?
Mrs Carter?
Mrs Wilkins, I see.
Wilkins太太 知道了
但你以前是Carter太太是吗?
But I am right in thinking
you were a Mrs Carter?
- Mickey被害之后他很照顾我们
- Thursday督察?
He looked out for us after Mickey
was killed. Inspector Thursday?
他每月末都会给我们寄钱
He sent me money
at the end of each month.
Right up until
when I got married again.
一直到我再婚
He'd taken Mickey under his wing,
see.
他一直都很照顾Mickey
从小警员开始
From a young constable.
Only that night...
那天晚上
Mickey一个人去见他的线人
Mickey went to see this informant
by himself.
结果那是个陷阱
It turned out he'd been set up.
It'd have only been a beating,
everyone said.
所有人都说 只是要打他一顿
But whoever it was went too far.
但是不管那是谁 下手太重
Thursday先生很自责
Mr Thursday blamed himself.
我跟他说没必要 但是他不接受
I told him there was no need
but he wouldn't have it.
Then when nobody got charged and
they started saying what they did
about Mickey...
然后没有人被起诉 他们开始说起
他们对Mickey做的那些事情
things got bad.
情况就越来越坏了
Fred当时有自己的小家庭
Fred had a young family himself.
他得照顾他们 确保他们的安全
He had to look out for them,
make sure they were kept safe.
Enjoying that sandwich?
三明治好吃吗?
It's all right.
还凑合
你经常来这里吗
Do you come here often?
Joan 是吧?
Joan, ain't it?
Who wants to know?
你是谁?
You're from down the Moonlight.
你是Moonlight的人
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right.
我叫Vince
Vince.
Can you give a little message
to your old man for me?
你能给你爸带个口信吗?
跟他说...
You tell him...
If you've got something to say to
my dad, you can tell him yourself.
如果你有什么要跟我爸说 你可以当面对他讲
如果你有种的话
If you can find the guts.
兄弟
Ah, matey.
That envelope you had in London,
Forensics confirms it was Coke
Norris's handwriting.
你从伦敦拿回来的信封
法医确认那是Coke Norris的笔迹
It was sent last post
the night he died.
那是他死的当晚最后一批信
Thanks.
什么
谢谢
Looks like Miss Vallens is on
the level, sir.
Georgina Bannard had a string of
soliciting convictions to her name.
看来Vallens小姐说的是实话 长官
I say her name truth is, she gave
a different alias every time
she got nicked.
Georgina Bannard这个名下有一长串的卖淫记录
说是她的名字 实际上她每次被抓
都会报不同的名字
Marion Childs, June Buckridge,
Betty Brinker.
Right.
Marion Childs June Buckridge Betty Brinker
Better let Mr Bright know
where we are.
好吧
You didn't tell him... the old man?
我们得赶紧让Bright先生知道我们进展到哪了
About the other night
with Joanie at the Moonlight?
你没跟他说吧?
Oh...
那天晚上我和Joanie在Moonlight的事
如果是你的话 我会说的
I would have if it was you.
No, you wouldn't.
不 你不会的
你看
Look...
you've got your Sergeant's coming up
tomorrow.
你明天就要警长考试了
What if I could get you a look
at the exam paper?
要是我能帮你搞到考卷呢?
If you don't pass, you'll be stuck
on general enquiries for another
year.
你要是没过 又得值一年班
你想那样吗?
Is that what you want?
I'm trying to do you a favour.
我是为你好
才不是
No.
你就是想收买我
You're trying to buy me off.
你要真是想帮我...
If you want to do me a favour...
对她好点
don't mess her about.
All right?
行不
没错 那是我的鬼画符
Yeah, that's my scrawl.
我从Wolsey Gardens接的他
I picked him up from Wolsey Gardens.
Old boy, 50s, a don, I took him for.
- 年龄挺大 50多了吧 应该是个教授
How come?
- 为什么
On account of the briefcase.
他拎的手提箱啊
I remember him cos he gave me
a ten bob tip.
我记得他因为他给了我十先令的小费
What time was this?
那时几点
Round half-seven.
7点半左右
- 你载他去了哪里
Where did you take him?
- 火车站 等了他一会 然后再回来
The station. Wait and return.
I took it he must be meeting
someone, only he wasn't in there
five minutes.
我猜他应该是去见谁了吧 他进去没五分钟
There we are, sir.
给你 先生
谢谢
Thank you very much.
385.
稍等
One moment.
你的箱子 先生
Here we are, sir.
Thank you.
谢谢
我以为我们已经有了Coke Norris教授的公文包
I thought we had Professor
Coke Norris's briefcase.
So did whoever killed him,
but there were two.
凶手也这么认为 但实际上他有两个
我们在另一条街上找到的一个 还有这一个
The one found in the next street
to where he was run over and this.
- 你从哪里找到的
- 火车站的行李寄存处
Where did you come by it? In the
left-luggage office at the station.
That's what the raffle ticket was
for.
那张带数字的纸条就是寄存号码
他去Baidley学院的路上叫了辆出租
He got a taxi there on the way to
Baidley College.
他带着第一个公文包进了车站 把这个留在了那
He goes into the station with the
first briefcase, leaves this one
inside,
then comes out carrying the same one
he went in with no-one watching
any the wiser.
然后出来的时候是拎着同一个包 没人会发现
- 那里面是什么
- 我还没来得及详细检查 长官
So what's in it? I haven't had
a chance to examine it in detail,
but it appears to be a list of
financial transactions,
但是看起来是一堆金钱交易
Coke Norris能找到的Baidley学院和地方议会之间
specifically every bribe and
backhander Coke Norris was able to
uncover
between Baidley College
and the council.
所有的行贿和受贿
The council? I thought I'd made
Division's views on this quite
clear?
地方议会?我以为我已经把上面的意思转达得很清楚了
我还没来得及跟Morse说那件事
I haven't had a chance to put Morse
in the picture as yet, sir.
Let me save you the trouble.
那我帮你省点麻烦
How the council and the college
conduct their business is a matter
for them.
地方议会和学院之间怎么进行交易是他们的事情
就算这牵涉贪汚?
Even if it involves corrupt
practices?
You've said yourself, you don't have
time to examine this dossier in
detail.
你已说你没时间详细检查这些文件
乍看起来有嫌疑
What at first glance may appear
suspect
might turn out on further
examination to be quite innocent.
经详细检查后可能是清白
我相信Baidley学院的院长可以澄清任何误解
I'm sure the Master at Baidley will
be able to clear up any
misunderstanding.
不可以再打扰Baidley学院的院长  这是我的最后决定
The Master at Baidley is not to be
troubled further and that is my
final word on the subject!
Coke Norris may have been onto
something between the council
and the college,
Coke Norris 可能与地方议会和学院有什么交割
but there's nothing in here
which ties the deal up with Kasper.
但是没什么证据可连结到Kasper
He's involved.
Don't you worry about that.
他有关连
- 你不用管
He's in it up to his neck.
他完全和这有关
'去看了白鲸?'
'Hast seen the white whale?'
Joan说那晚她在 Moonlight做的事?
My Joan say what she was doing
at the Moonlight the other night?
那些在银行的女孩在晚上的兼职
Works night out.
Girls from the bank.
为什么你在那里?
How come you were there?
I was working on the case...
我在查这件案...
looking for Georgina Bannard.
还在找 Georgina Bannard
After I'd told you to steer clear?
在我已叫你远离这案?
Look, I don't need protecting, sir.
我不需要你保护 先生
Don't you?
No.
是吗?
- 不
我不会像 Mickey Carter
I won't end up like Mickey Carter.
你又怎么会知道?
What would you know about it?
我去见了他的遗孀
I saw his widow.
You did what?
Yeah, when I was in London.
- 你见了谁?
- 我在伦敦的时候
- 背着我
Going behind my back.
No, sir, doing my job.
- 没有 长官 尽责而已
Your job's what I say it is.
You'd no business.
你的职责是我让你做什么你就做什么
你和那个没关系
If it has a bearing on the case,
then it is my business.
如果那影响到案子的话 那就是我的职责
You weren't gonna tell me.
你又不肯告诉我
Was it Vic Kasper?
是Vic Kasper下的手吗?
没法证明是他
Couldn't prove it.
调查发现Mickey从他那收的钱
Investigations started turning up
Mickey had been on the take.
他当然没有 那是个陷害
He hadn't, of course,
it was a fit-up.
But the brass didn't want to know.
但是上层们不想继续查下去
They brushed it under the carpet.
就直接结案了
You wouldn't let that go?
你不会就这么善罢甘休的
Oh, I let it go, all right.
噢 我善罢甘休了 真的
To my shame.
我很惭愧
我走了 让他们就这么把Mickey Carter的好名声
跟他的尸体一起埋葬了
I walked away and let them bury
Mickey Carter's good name along
with his body.
他们会利用你的弱点
They come at you through what you
care about.
That's why you moved to Oxford?
所以你就搬来了牛津?
差不多吧
More or less.
但就到此为止了
But this is where it stops.
你没猜错
You were right.
It wasn't the Army...
我不是在军队里
where I learnt to shoot.
学的射击
我12岁的时候
When I was 12...
the first Christmas...
我母亲去世后
after my mother...
第一个圣诞节
我父亲给我买了把手枪
my father bought me a pistol.
他以前会带我去打兔子
He used to take me out on the common
after rabbits.
Make a man.
培养男子汉
你在这怎么样了?
How are you settling in?
I've an unpleasant feeling of dead
man's shoes.
我感觉很不自在
在把Al的最后一点东西打包
Just boxing up the last of
Al's stuff.
Do you have a minute?
Actually, I'm a bit pushed for time.
- 你有空吗?
- 实际上 我有点忙
I said I'd take Millie
to the undertaker's.
我跟Millie说了要送她去殡仪馆
你知道院长怎么会有
Have you any idea how the Master
may have come by the key
Coke Norris教授伦敦公寓的钥匙的吗?
to Professor Coke Norris's flat
in London?
Dr Kern?
Kern博士
只是些学院的八卦
It's just college gossip.
有阵子 Alistair把他伦敦公寓的钥匙
借给了Frobisher
Some time ago, Alistair loaned
Frobisher the key to their London
flat.
He had some symposium to attend.
他要参加个座谈会
但是...
But...
the Master took advantage
somewhat.
院长肯定是利用了那个
He had a second key cut?
他复制了钥匙?
And made it available to those
fellows who needed a place to stay
in London.
然后借给那些需要暂住伦敦的家伙们
Married fellows?
已婚的
我想知道同事的婚外情
I suppose intimate knowledge
of his colleagues' affairs
对院长来说没坏处吧
尤其是需要投票通过Booth Hill计划的时候
wouldn't do the Master any harm
when it came to a vote on Booth Hill.
Blackmail, you mean?
你是说 敲诈?
It's a way of persuading any
waiverers sympathetic to Coke
Norris's cause.
是一种可以说服那些同情Coke Norris的
摇摆不定人的一种办法
你觉得呢?
Come on, Maurie.
快点 Maurie
You're not gonna throw something
at me again, are you?
你不会又要冲我扔东西了吧这次?
Flag of truce. I'm offering
a ceasefire.
What ceasefire?
休战旗 我是来提议停火的
48 hours head start, chance to wind
things up and be on your way, before
we come after you.
停什么火
Come after me for what?
I told you, I'm retired.
在我们开始收拾你之前
给你48小时收拾东西离开这儿
We've got Coke Norris's briefcase,
Vic.
收拾我 为什么? 我跟你说过我退休了
我们拿到了Coke Norris的公文包了 Vic
It's all there in black and white,
every bent deal you put together
to land the Booth Hill contract.
You been on the funny fags?
你为了搞到Booth Hill的合约做的每一笔肮脏交易
都白纸黑字写在里面
I don't want anyone else getting
hurt.
- 你是不是抽了大麻了?
- 我不想其他人受伤
所以这是我的提议 接不接受随你
So that's the offer.
Take it or leave it.
Can I open the box?
我能打开盒子吗?
说真的 Fred 我真的不知道你在说什么
Serious, Fred, I don't know what
you're talking about.
但是我告诉你 我哪里也不去
But I'll tell you this.
I'm going nowhere.
你家Joan没和你说吗?
Your Joan not spoke to you yet?
What about my Joan?
我家Joan怎么了?
I guess not.
看来是没有
She was down here the other night
with that copper.
她上次来的时候和那个警察一起
What copper?
哪个警察?
That boy of yours.
你手下年轻的那个
Made a nice couple, I thought.
我觉得看上去挺登对
你什么?
You what?
你在说Morse?
You talking about Morse?
It must weigh on a father,
that kind of responsibility.
当父亲肯定很不容易 责任重大
她长得不错
She's a good-looking girl.
It'd be a tragedy...
会是个悲剧...
但你无法24小时守着他们 不是吗?
But you can't be there to watch them
all the time, can you?
Those papers you've got on
Booth Hill.
你手里的Booth Hill的文件
我今天就要
I want them today.
That's how things are gonna go
from here on, Fred.
事情就是这么发展下去的 Fred
你最好早点习惯
You better get used to it.
我要单独跟你谈谈
I want a word with you in private.
抱歉长官 Morse的妹妹
Sorry, sir. Morse's sister.
Joycie?
冷静
Calm down.
I'll be there soon as I can.
我马上就过去
Got your ticket?
Yeah.
- 拿好票了?
- 拿了
Sorry about this, it's probably just
another false alarm.
很抱歉 说不准又是什么事都没
Family. A man only gets one father.
家人嘛 每个人只有一个爹
We'll manage.
我们应付得过来
What was it you wanted to talk to me
about?
- 刚才你想跟我说什么
- 没事可以等
It'll keep.
I know you went out with Joan
the other night.
我知道你那晚和Joan一起出去了
Be good to her.
对她好点
来吧
Right.
You're back. The way you went out
this morning, I didn't get a chance
to do your sandwiches.
你回来了啊 你今天早上走的太匆忙
我都没来得及给你做三明治
Have you got time now?
- 你这会有时间吗?\
No, I just popped back to get
my pipe.
- 没 我就回来拿个烟斗
- 我落在小棚里了
I left it in the shed.
I'll do you a quick round.
- 我马上给你做一个
Fred?
I can't believe how many of these
Alistair's had out of the library.
我真不敢相信Alistair怎么从图书馆借了这么多书
阿伽门农那本不是
Not the Agamemnon, though.
是Andrew Maidenhead送的礼物
他是你之前的初级导师
That was a present from Andrew
Maidenhead, the junior man before
you.
我年轻的仰慕者 如果你相信这事的话
My young admirer,
if you can believe such a thing.
我为什么不信呢
Why wouldn't I?
He was a sweet boy but in the end
I had to have Alistair talk to the
Master about him.
他是个好孩子
但是最后我只好让Alistair跟院长说了他的事
Heavens! Let me help.
天呐 让我来吧
没关系 我没事
No, no, I'm fine.
You've got to give them
what they want.
你得把他们想要的东西给他们
Start down that road,
there's no end to it.
- 一旦走上那条路 就没有回头了
- 但是他们威胁的是Joan
This is Joan they're threatening!
I won't let anything happen.
我不会让任何事情发生的
You've got my word.
我保证
All right?
好不好?
Something from Companies House
for Morse.
公司注册处有东西给Morse
It found its way onto my desk marked
'urgent'.
不知道怎么到了我的桌上 标着急件
I'm afraid his father's
taken a turn for the worse, sir.
他父亲的情况突然恶化了 长官
I see. Where the hell is everyone?
明白了 见鬼人都去哪了?
2先令一盒你就笑了 钱好赚嘛
Two bob a pack and you're laughing.
It's easy money.
看看这谁
There you are.
Where's Vic?
- Vic在哪
- 只有我在
It's just me.
我是来找领头的 不是找打工的
It's the engineer I'm here for,
not the oily rag.
You ain't got what I told you
to get you here for nothing.
我要你做的事情不会让你白做的
Where's the papers?
- 那些文件呢
- 安全着呢
In safekeeping.
Fetch him now.
找他过来
你以为你能活着离开这里?
You think you're walking out
of here?
I know you're not,
nor is your old man.
我知道你不能 还有你老头
至于之后的事 我无所谓
After that, I don't much care.
Whoa, whoa!
- Fred?
- 我告诉过你离开这里 Vic
Fred?
I told you to clear out, Vic.
Now it's this.
现在轮到这个了
Wait a minute. What for?
等等 为什么?
说说Coke Norris那事? 不知道?
How about Coke Norris? No?
All right.
好吧
Try the young girl we found
with a bullet in her skull.
那就说说那个后脑中了一枪的女孩
我已经洗手不干了 我告诉过你
I'm retired, I told you.
那么Carter呢 这个我们都知道的
Carter, then.
We can agree on Carter.
All fair's, Fred, water under.
Fred 所有的事情 都已经过去了
威胁我的女儿
Threatening my Joan?
Water under?
过去了吗?
- 那跟我没关系
- 那你真是不走运了
That's none of mine.
Bad luck for you, then.
长官
Sir.
- 别这样 他说的实话
- 你别管 Morse
Don't, he's telling the truth.
Stay out of this, Morse.
Thank God, someone with some sense.
谢天谢地 终于还有人有点理智
What's this?
那是什么?
- 文件吗?
- 算是
Papers?
After a fashion.
这是Landersmine建筑公司合伙人的一些报道
These are the articles of association
for Landersmine Construction.
Hold on.
等等
四个平等合伙人
Four shareholders, equal partners.
Fletcher兄弟俩 Sid和Gerald
你儿子Vince 还有Cynthia Riley
Sid and Gerald Fletcher,
your son Vince and Cynthia Riley.
什么?
What?
我什么也不知道 Vic Vince
I don't know nothing about this,
Vic. Vince!
Tell him.
快告诉他
She don't, Dad. Cyn's been loyal.
她确实不知道 爸爸 Cyn一直都很忠于你
I put it in her name as a surprise
for you.
我把她的名字加进去 想给你个惊喜
你肯定会吃惊的
You would have been surprised.
Your son's put together a firm at the
Fletchers' to build houses on Booth
Hill.
你儿子和Fletcher兄弟一起组建了个公司
准备在Booth Hill建房子
- 没有违法
- 是的
No law against it.
No.
But there is a law against bribing
public officials.
但是有法律禁止向公职人员行贿
have been cashed over the past 12
months
Landersmine建筑公司开出了总计6,000镑的支票 在过去的12个月内
被房屋署的高级规划官Mark Carlisle分批兑现
by Mark Carlisle senior planning
officer in the Housing Department.
It's between me and the boy, Fred.
这是我和孩子之间的事 Fred
You let me straighten him out.
Can't do it, Vic.
- 你让我好好管教他
- 做不到 Vic
警察 不许动 放下抢
Police, nobody move!
Drop the guns!
把枪放下
Guns down!
- 都在控制之下吗 Thursday?
All in order, Thursday?
- 是的 长官
Yes, sir.
All in order.
都在控制之下
Morse?
Vince Kasper 我以向公务员行贿之名拘捕你
Vince Kasper, I'm arresting you
for conspiring to bribe a public
official.
你可以不说话 但是你所说的一切都将记录下来
You don't have to say anything
but anything you do say may be
written down
and can be given in evidence
against you.
成为呈堂证供
Strange
Strange.
We'll also need you to come down the
station for questioning, Miss Riley.
我们还需要你来警局接受问话 Riley小姐
回伦敦吧 Kasper先生
Go back to London, Mr Kasper.
牛津不适合你
Oxford's not for you.
Workhouse rules.
劳改工厂守则
I put you on a train.
我看你上了火车的
I got off.
我下来了
So if it wasn't Vince or Vic who did
for Coke Norris and the girl,
那如果不是Vince或Vic杀了Coke Norris和那个姑娘的话
we're back to where we started.
- 我们又回到了开始的地方
- 是啊
Yes.
Exactly where we started.
正是我们开始的地方
Mrs Coke Norris?
Coke Norris太太
Oh, Inspector.
督察
Constable Morse.
Morse警员
- 前门开着
- 请进 进来
The front door was already open.
Come in, do.
One or two questions we need to put
to you about your husband's death.
有关你先生的案子 我们还有几个问题要问你
好的 没问题
Of course. Please.
The morning of the day he was killed,
you took a train to London the 10:40?
他被害的那天上午 你是坐的10点40的车去的伦敦?
Right. And the day you came back,
what train did you catch?
- 是的
- 那你回来坐的几点的车?
The er...9:50.
呃 9点50的
So you'd have left your flat at what
time, about half-past nine?
那你离开公寓的时候 差不多是9点半?
差不多吧 是的
Around that, yes.
After the first post.
Oh, er... yes.
- 过了上午送邮件的时候?
- 是的
But when I visited your London flat,
I found a letter addressed to your
husband on the mat.
但是我去你伦敦的公寓时
发现垫子上有一封信是给你先生的
It would have arrived that morning.
应该是那天早上到的
我很好奇 你为什么没把它带回牛津给你先生
I'm curious why didn't you bring it
back to Oxford with you for him?
你是不是那天去了伦敦 但是当天就回了牛津
Isn't the truth of it that you
caught the train up to London but
returned to Oxford that same day
in the car kept at your mews flat?
开的是你家楼下停的那辆车
当然不是 太荒谬了
Of course not, that's ridiculous.
我怎么可能 我都不会开车
How could I? I don't even drive.
你不会 你没有驾照
No, you don't have a licence.
But you did drive an ambulance
in the war.
但是你战时的确开救护车
- 你以为是我撞了Alistair?
- 不
You think I ran Alistair over?
No.
你知道你先生那天晚上要去Baidley学院
所以你跟踪了他
You knew your husband was going
to Baidley College that evening
so followed him.
You lured him into the car
under some pretext or other.
你随便编了个理由让他上了车
You drove him out of town
to some private place,
你开车出了城 到了个偏僻的地方
说车没油了 或是制造了什么机械故障
where you stalled the car or
otherwise engineered a mechanical
fault.
这也太晚了
Ridiculously late.
You got him back into the car,
then found a quiet street in Oxford
你把他弄进车 找了牛津一条比较安静的街区
扔下他的尸体 做成撞人逃逸的样子
where you dumped his body to be
taken for the victim of
a hit-and-run.
The squeal of brakes was
a nice touch.
刹车声是个好点子
但是你差点搞砸了
But you almost ruined it.
You'd dumped his body but overlooked
his briefcase and driven back with it
to London.
你抛完尸却没注意到他的公文包还在车里
就这么一直带回了伦敦
So you took an early train back to
Oxford and left it in the street.
所以你一大早就坐车回到牛津
然后把它留在了街上
那就是为什么你错过了早上的投递
你在邮递员到之前就已经离开了
That's why you missed the first post.
You'd left before it arrived.
我为什么要伤害Alistair?
Why would I hurt Alistair?
Because you'd become infatuated with
Ian Kern to the point of obsession.
因为你对Ian Kern着迷到了疯狂的地步
In your head, you'd created
the fantasy of a future together.
在你的脑海里 你想像你们在一起美好的将来
而土地出售的提案又让你产生了经济上的幻想
When the land sale arose, you saw
a way of financing that delusion.
作为初级教员 Kern博士从中没有办法获利
但是如果他变成了资深教员呢?
As a junior fellow, Dr Kern stood to
gain nothing from the deal but what
if he became a senior?
Professor Coke Norris confided
every detail of his campaign to you.
Coke Norris教授跟你说了
他计划的每一步 是不是?
We were of one mind.
我们什么都告诉对方
Even so, you must have been alarmed
when he told you of a pupil
尽管这样 当他告诉你有个学生有着重要的消息
who had vital information whereby
the land sale might be derailed.
能破坏土地出售 你肯定很紧张
You followed Judy Vallens,
found out where she lived.
你跟踪了Judy Vallens 找到她的住处
但是你跟我们犯了同一个错
But you made the same error
that we did
把她的室友Georgina Bannard
误认为是Vallens小姐
and mistook her flatmate,
Georgina Bannard, for Miss Vallens.
你朝她头部开了一枪
You shot her in the head.
You shot her, then returned to her
flat for her clothes to create the
impression she'd gone.
你杀了她 然后返回她家拿走她的衣服 做出她离开的假象
假设你说的是真的 你有什么证据?
Where's your evidence
for any of this charade?
You told me the last time your
husband was in London was for a prom,
上次你跟我说你和你先生去伦敦看演奏会
Haffner和马勒第4交响曲
the Haffner and the Mahler 4.
那场音乐会是9月3日星期五晚上的
That concert took place
on Friday 3rd September,
the same weekend your car was in
for its annual service.
那个周末你的车送去年检了
The car was returned from a garage
in Mayfair on the Monday morning.
车周一早上从Mayfair的一家修车厂送回来
据你所说 车一直就停在你家楼下
According to you, it has been parked
outside your mews ever since.
Right.
- 是啊
- 好
So how do you explain
the difference in mileage
那你怎么解释修好车后修车记录里写的里程数
between the total written down in
the log book after its service
and its current total,
和实际里程数之间的差距呢
这中间相差了大概120英里
差不多就是伦敦到牛津往返的距离
a distance of 120-odd miles, roughly
that of a round trip from London
to Oxford?
如果你是用车子来装你先生的尸体
是会留下证据的
If you transported your husband in
the car, there will be evidence
地毯上 车座和靠背之间的缝隙的血滴
a spot of blood on the carpet,
in the crack between the seat
and the back rest.
Mrs Coke Norris, you've killed two
people, all for some delusional
fantasy of a romance
Coke Norris太太 你杀了两个人
就为了一个不切实际的幻想
with someone
who finds your attentions oppressive.
而且还是对一个觉得你的关心
让他难以忍受的人
Ian是爱我的
Ian loved me.
他爱过我
He did.
I know he did. He just needed time.
我知道他爱过 他只是需要一点时间
你还是去拿外套吧
Perhaps you'd like to get your coat.
Actually, I think I should like
to sit down for a moment.
其实 我想坐一会
Sir?
长官
Kern博士在哪
Where's Dr Kern?
Coke Norris太太?
Mrs Coke Norris?
在书房
In the study.
After all I'd done.
我为他做了那么多 那么多
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
我是Morse探员 牛津警局的
This is DC Morse, Oxford Police.
I need an ambulance...
我需要一辆救护车...
Morse?
All right, watch yourself
on these steps.
好了 当心台阶
Agh!
Come on.
当心
I've made as best a running repair
as I can.
我尽最大可能给你紧急处理了一下
但是你真的要去趟医院
But you really need to go to
Casualty.
我没时间
I don't have time.
The doctor said we should talk
to you.
医生说我们要跟你说说话
有什么你需要的吗?
Anything you need?
我要过几天回去
I'll be back in a few days.
可惜你没能早点过来看一下
It's a pity you didn't come and see
me a bit sooner.
The leg will mend,
腿会没事的
but in middle-age you may well find
yourself saddled with a limp.
但到了中年 你可能会有点小瘸
Nothing serious, just if you're
overtired or the weather turns.
不严重 只是你太疲劳
或是天气不好的时候会发作
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.